A Guide to the Paul A. Lewis papers, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Scientific Staff FA175
Rockefeller Archive Center
Paul A. Lewis papers, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Scientific Staff
1908-1950, undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
Lewis, Paul A.
FA175
0.44 Cubic Feet 1 box
1 box 2.5" letter
Biographical/Historical note
Paul Adin Lewis, 1879-1929, pathologist at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1908-1929.
Biographical note
1879 Born April 14, Chicago, Illinois
1904 M.D., University of Pennsylvania
1904-1905 Resident in Pathology, Boston City Hospital
1905-1908 Assistant in Antitoxin Laboratory, Massachusetts State Board of Health, Boston
1906-1908 Fellow in Comparative Pathology, Harvard University, Massachusetts
1908-1910 Associate in Pathology, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, New York
1910-1923 Director, Laboratory of Henry Phipps Institute, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
1921-1923 Professor of Experimental Pathology, University of Pennsylvania
1923- Associate Member, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
1917-1921 Lieutenant/Commander, U.S. Naval Reserve
1928-1929 Study of yellow fever in Bahia, Brazil, under the auspices of the Rockefeller Foundation's International Health Board
1929 Died June 30, Bahia, Brazil (of yellow fever)
Member of: American Association of Pathologists and Bacteriologists, Association of American Physicians, American Association for the Advancement of Science, National Tuberculosis Association (director), Sigma Xi, Alpha Omega Alpha
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 L588
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Medical sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Tuberculosis; Life sciences; Diseases; Pathology; Disease management -- Lurín River Valley (Peru); Prevention and health; Medical education; Medical research; Biochemistry; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University; Lewis, Paul A.
- Administrative correspondence, 1908-1950 (Box 1)
  - 1908-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1927-1929 June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1929-1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Obituary in Science by Simon Flexner (extra copies stored with S. Flexner reprints/reprint file.) 9 August 1929 issue, 1929 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Sancrysin" report, 1925 October (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Scope and Contents note
  Several copies.
- Photos (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Newspaper clippings of obituary articles (Box 1, Folder 10)